Welcome back, sir.
欢迎回来 长官
What have you done?
你们做了什么？
What we needed to in order to save you, Silas.
为了挽救您的生命所必须做的 塞拉斯
I'm one of them.
我…成他们中的一员了！
The logical evolution of MECH's experiments and biotech.
借助生物科技实验的终极研究成果
Your brain fused with the donor's nervous and skeletal systems.
您的大脑与捐赠者的神经和骨骼系统连接在了一起
The perfect meld of man and machine. Exquisite.
人类与机器的完美结合 如此精湛…
Thank you all for your dedication and a lifetime of service.
感谢你们这一生为我所做的贡献
But I now seem more suited to keep the exclusive company of titans.
不过 我现在觉得自己更适合与那群巨人为伍了
Colonel Leland Bishop.
我是莱兰・毕晓普上校
Bulkhead, you really mustn't allow yourself to decline.
隔板 你真的不能让自己这么衰弱下去
Yeah, Bulk. You got to pull yourself out of this funk.
对啊 小隔 你应该从沮丧中走出来！
What's the use?
有什么用？
You need to regain your strength.
你真的需要加强体能
The time will come when...
只要假以时日 你就能…
When what? When all of you will need an assist?
能怎么样？帮上你们大家的忙？
Isn't that what the new guy's for?
那要新来的家伙干嘛？
Hey, Bulkhead, I've been thinking. With your injury and all,
嘿 隔板 我一直在想 考虑到你的伤势
you might want to take advantage of the armor I snagged from Starscream.
你不妨试试我从红蜘蛛那儿弄来的盔甲
Instant muscle suit!
即穿即用的肌肉外套！
You think I need a crutch?!
你认为我得去拄拐？
Bulkhead, I needed that!
隔板！那个我还有用呐！
Out of my way, rookie!
别挡道 新兵蛋子！
He can walk!
他能走路了！
Looks like he's fit for duty to me.
要我说 他完全可以执行任务了！
You don't even know what you're talking about.
你甚至都不知道自己在说什么
You've got to be kidding, Raf.
你不是开玩笑吧 拉夫！
You of all people grounded?
你这种模范学生 被禁足了？
Big time. I misplaced some homework and blew a couple of tests.
闹大了！我漏掉了一些作业 还搞砸了几门考试
Translation: "A-" instead of "A."
搞砸了是指：成绩从“A”变成了“A-”
I'm probably spending too much time at the base.
可能我耗在基地的时间过多了吧
Rafael, I hope you're not on the phone in there.
拉斐尔 我希望你没在那儿打电话
No, mama! Say hello to Bee for me.
没 妈妈 帮我跟小蜂打个招呼
By time I improve these grades, I'm off team Prime.
还有 在我的成绩提高之前 我没法呆在领袖卫队了
Just when we get one back, we lose another.
好容易回来一个 立马又走了一个
Strange.
奇怪啊
Lord Megatron, it appears that Breakdown's signal has popped back online,
威震天陛下 看起来打击的生命信号又出现了
all be it corrupted.
尽管受到了污染
Investigate with caution. It may well be an Autobot trick.
谨慎前往调查 这很可能是汽车人的陷阱
I certainly hope not.
这是当然
Breakdown may act a brute, but he's a maestro behind a rotary buffer.
打击表面上是一只猛兽 但在旋转缓冲器下隐藏着一颗艺术家的心
Breakdown, where have you...
打击！这些日子你上…
Breakdown, what happened to you?
打击？谁欺负你了？
There lies a tale which won't be nearly as interesting to Megatron as this.
这说来话长 而且威震天对这个一定更感兴趣！
So, take me to your leader.
所以 带我去见你的头目吧
At 16:30 hours, a satellite was stolen from a high-security military bolt.
下午4点30分时 一颗卫星从高安全等级的军需库中被盗
Surveillance shows the Decepticon known as Breakdown at the scene.
监控录像显示那个名叫打击的霸天虎离开过现场
Haven't seen him in a while.
有阵子没见过他了
It looks like Breakdown entered the base in vehicle mode
似乎在打击以汽车形态进入基地的时候
with someone behind the wheel.
车上还有个人
A Decepticon paired with a human?
一个霸天虎和一个人类成双入对？
And I have a pretty good hunch who.
此外我基本上猜出那人是谁了
The stolen satellite was project Damocles.
被偷的卫星原属于达摩克利斯计划
Invented by Silas.
塞拉斯发明的东西
I guess the former Colonel Bishop wanted it back.
我猜是前上校毕晓普想翻旧帐了
Yeah, I thought Silas was paste!
是啊 我还以为塞拉斯已经成过去式了！
So did I.
包括我在内！
Agent Fowler, even if he were alive,
福勒探员 就算他还活着
are you suggesting that Silas has allied MECH with the Decepticons?
你认为他能和霸天虎勾结在一起么？
I highly doubt that Megatron would entertain such an idea.
我极度怀疑威震天会考虑这个主意！
Why not? The human-bot alliance works for us.
为什么不呢？我们人机合作得就很不错嘛！
Most of the time.
大多数时候吧…
Knockout, what is this abomination?!
击倒 这个令人作呕的东西是什么？
And why have you brought it here?
你竟然还把它带到这儿来？
I am Silas, as in cybernetic life augmented by symbiosis.
我是塞拉斯 全称“增强型人机共存生命体”
I come with a proposition.
我来是有个提议
This is the human who dissected Breakdown.
这就是那个把打击解剖的人类！
Please, my liege, allow me to return the favor.
我的君王 请您允许我以牙还牙
I propose that you not overlook the one asset that provides Optimus Prime an advantage... at least, on this world.
我建议您不要忽略一个让擎天柱占尽上风的资产 至少在这个星球上
And that would be?
你是指…
The human factor.
人类因素
Look around you, Silas!
看看你的周围吧 塞拉斯！
I command an army from a mighty warship.
我统领着一支来自强大战舰上的军队
What could a human possibly offer?
相较之下 一个渺小的人类能为我提供什么？！
I am no ordinary human, and this is no ordinary weapon.
我可不是普通的人类 这也并非普通的武器
Damocles is a particle-beam cannon so powerful it can slice up the Pentagon like a birthday cake
达摩克利斯是一门粒子炮 它的力量足以把五角大楼像生日蛋糕一样切开
or give everyone on Mount Rushmore a mohawk, all from a satellite in orbit.
从卫星轨道上用那东西 我能把拉什莫尔山的人都剃成莫霍克头
It's the work of a madman. And in Megatron's hands...
这是一个疯子的发明 还落在了威震天手里
A threat to anyone, anywhere on the planet.
一把利剑 高悬在这星球上每个人的头顶？
With pinpoint accuracy at the flick of a switch.
只需轻轻碰一下开关
And what is it that you... wish in return?
那么你想要什么回报？
Merely a place at the table.
只要能在您这里获得一席之地…
The Cons may have the satellite, but they can't use it without the interface code.
虎子们或许能夺取卫星 但没有接入密码就无法控制它
The only existing copy is stored on the secured servers at headquarters in Colorado.
唯一的副本被保存在卡罗拉多州总部的安全服务器上
We must keep the code out of Decepticon hands at all costs.
我们必须不惜一切代价阻止霸天虎获得密码
It's roll time.
表演时间到了！
Ep, ep... ! I have not yet cleared you for active duty, nor are you ready to roll.
那个…我还没说你能执行任务呢 更别说你现在根本没做好准备！
Attention, all personnel are ordered to evacuate immediately.
注意！所有人员紧急疏散
We have a level 5 radiation leak. Repeat, evacuate immediately.
这里发生5级生化辐射泄露 重复 立即疏散！
The Decepticons have proceeded us. We must secure the command center.
霸天虎捷足先登了！我们必须保护指挥中心！
The Autobots have arrived.
汽车人也到了！
Megatron, relax.
威震天 放轻松！
Lord Megatron.
威震天…陛下
Soundwave may need to download the code in order to remotely operated Damocles from here on your warship,
声波或许需要下载密码 才能让您在战舰里直接遥控达摩克利斯
but while jacked into the mainframe, Damocles is his to command.
不过一旦侵入了中央处理器 他就能任意控制达摩克利斯了！
Soundwave, prepare to beta test.
声波 准备进行测试！
Promising.
大有搞头啊…
Fall back!
撤退！
Ratchet, we require backup.
救护车 请求支援！
- I'm there. - You can't yet!
马上就到！
Can you remotely disable project Damocles under Agent Fowler's advisement?
你能按福勒探员的意见来远程关闭达摩克利斯吗？
On a human-based computer network
用人类的电脑网络？
without my backup? Without Rafael?
在缺少助手…缺少拉斐尔的情况下？
Wha... what are you guys doing here?
你们干嘛来这儿？
Son, your planet needs you.
孩子 地球母亲需要你
Autobots, we must draw its fire to distract from Rafael's efforts.
汽车人 我们必须把它的注意力从拉斐尔那里引开
Somehow I don't think that'll be a problem.
我倒觉得这完全不是问题
Ratchet, you've got to send me in.
救护车 你必须送我过去！
So you can be an even easier target?
好让你当个移动标靶？
You have yet to regain your full range of motion!
你现在连行动都不能自理
But Breakdown's back. He's my archenemy.
可是打击回来了 他可是我的老冤家
Come on, even the kids are in on the action!
拜托 连孩子们都在忙乎呢！
Very well, Bulkhead. You are cleared for duty.
好吧 隔板 你现在可以去执行任务了
Yes!
太好了！
A duty of my choosing.
是我给你的任务！
I'm in, but I can't reach the targeting systems. Too many firewalls.
我黑进去了 但我没法接触目标系统 防火墙太多了
Come on, son. If the Cons make off with that interface code,
加油 孩子！要是虎子带着密码逃了
Damocles will light up the sky 24-7.
达摩克利斯可就能全天候在天上开火了！
Let them have the code. It won't do them any good without the satellite.
就让他们带走密码好了 反正那也没法帮他们使用卫星
Can't say I follow you.
我没听明白
All satellites have maneuvering thrusters so they can adjust their orbits.
任何卫星都会有推进器 这是他们用来调整轨道的
If I can break into the navigation subroutine, I can bring the whole satellite down.
如果我能黑进航行子程序 就能彻底关掉卫星
Great. Say, um... which way is the bathroom?
好极了！顺便 呃…洗手间在哪儿？
What? No! If my Mom sees you...
什么？不！要是我妈妈看见你…
Relax. I trained in covert ops.
甭担心 叔叔可是在隐蔽行动中练过的
I don't care if you were trained by a ninja. My Mom has eyes in the back of your head!
你就是被忍者训练过我也不管 我妈的眼睛无处不在
An intruder in the system? Soundwave, we have a breach!
有人入侵了系统？声波 我们有漏洞了！
Jasper, Nevada. It can only be the Autobots' human allies.
贾斯帕 内华达 那只可能是汽车人的人类同盟
Then perhaps you should attend to the matter.
或许你可以把这件事处理一下！
Surely one of your subordinates is more suitable.
显然您的部下更适合执行这个任务
Now!
快去！
Clear shot! I'm going in!
畅通无阻 我要上了！
Scratch that.
还是再议吧！
Good night, hacker.
晚上好 黑客
Good call on curbside duty, Ratch.
我喜欢这支线任务 老救！
Been itching to trade pay with you again. Where you been, Breakdown?
我想你想的拳头发痒 你跑哪儿去了 打击？
Be patient. I'm about to send you there.
别着急 我马上就送你去那边见他
You're not Breakdown.
你不是打击？
But you are Bulkhead, and this is the last time you'll interfere with one of my operations.
但你是隔板 这是你最后一次干扰我的行动了
Silas?
塞拉斯？
In the flesh, in a manner of speaking.
在肉体上…从某种意义上来说
Bulkhead, do you read? Bulkhead!
隔板你听到了吗？隔板！
Optimus, I fear that Bulkhead requires immediate backup.
擎天柱 恐怕隔板需要紧急支援！
Oh, where did they hide the substringing?
可恶 他们都把参数藏在哪儿了？
FYI, you're low on T.P.
我说 你家卫生纸不多了
Reaction time is slow. You're favoring your right side.
反应太慢了 你太依赖右拳了
Legs are weak.
步法太乱
I'll show you weak.
让你见识一下什么叫乱！
You should have stayed in bed, Autobot.
你该躺在病床上的 汽车人
Assist... what the new guy's for.
我来支援 这是新人该干的！
One new guy to another...
听我这个老“新人”一言…
This is your final day on the job.
今天是你最后一次打卡了！
They're attempting to disable the satellite!
他们的意图是关闭卫星！
Silas, how difficult is it to squash a human child?!
塞拉斯 砸扁一个人类小孩对你来说就那么难吗！
Silas!
塞拉斯！
We have the codes? Then target the intruder and destroy him!
我们有密码了 直接瞄准黑客 消灭他！
This is our opportunity. Autobots, storm the command center.
我们的机会来了 汽车人 向指挥中心进攻！
I'm almost there.
就要成功了
Raf, rock on! It's moving.
干得好 拉夫！它动起来了！
Uh, that isn't me.
呃 那不是我干的…
Uh, guys... that's Jasper.
啊 伙计们？那是贾斯帕
Ooh, I can see my host parents' house.
哇唔 我能看到我监护人的房子！
And I can see my house right in their target sights.
而我能看到我家 就在目标范围内！
Any time, son.
他们随时会开火 孩子！
Full thruster burn.
全力推进！
Yes! You're a genius!
你…你真是个天才！
Rafael. Jorge Gonzales Esquivel! What is going on in here?
拉斐尔…？怎么这么吵 你到底在干什么？
Study group.
学习研讨会！
Silas, return to base immediately.
塞拉斯 立即返回基地！
Looks like someone's big plan just burned up in re-entry.
看来某人的宏伟计划又一次泡了汤！
And for the record, I studied every one of the Wrecker's battles.
说到雷霆救援队 我研究过你们的每一场战斗
There's hope for you yet, newbie.
你还是有希望入队的 新兵蛋子！
Silas, you have earned your place at the table.
塞拉斯 你已经赢得了你的席位
Lord Megatron, I am honored.
威震天陛下 这是我的荣幸
Knockout's dissection table.
在击倒的解剖台上！
Breakdown would be tickled.
打击会为此泉下有知的
No, lord Megatron. Why?
不 威震天陛下 为什么？
Because Damocles was the best you had to offer,
因为达摩克利斯是你所能提供的最好的东西
and it is no more. The human factor did indeed tip the scales...
而它现在已经没了 人类因素的确起到了决定性作用
in favor of my enemies.
而获益者是我的敌人！
He will be a fascinating case for study.
他会是个迷人的研究素材…
I will leave no fiber or fiber optic unexamined.
我会好好研究他 一片纤维都不会落下…
No, no. Megatron, I'm here to serve you!
不 不 威震天 我是来为您效忠的！
No! No! Nooo!
不 不 不！！！